Today, it is my pleasure to officially
introduce to you Archon, an open-source
AI agent that literally builds other AI
agents. And I've covered a bit on my
channel already, but I haven't given it
a proper introduction or shared with you
the crazy big ideas that I have for it.
I'm going to be using it both as a
teaching tool and also to eventually
build it into an absolute monster of an
AI agent that spins up other agents on
demand. And I'm doing it all in public
for you to follow along, learn from, and
contribute to if you want to be a part
of something big. And if we do this
right, Archon could easily be one of the
most important AI agents out there. Just
hear me out on this. Coding is
hands-down the biggest and strongest use
case for AI right now. And I'm not just
trying to get you on a hype train. Using
AI to code really does seem to be top of
mind for everyone, including every
company building LLMs. Just look at the
huge coding focus for Claude 3.7 Sonnet,
Deep Seek R1, Gwen 2.5 Coder. And I am
all over this right now because there is
a goldmine of opportunities for us to
build AI apps that use LLMs to help us
write code. Cuz here's the thing, there
are a lot of generalist AI coders out
there, like Windswept, Cursor, and
Klein. But not a lot of specialized AI
agents that can get the job done really
well for a specific framework or a
tackling specific problems. We have some
specialized tools like Bolt and
Levelable for creating incredible front
ends. But what about an AI coding
assistant that creates other AI agents,
runs them, and iterates on them? And we
need this because it's becoming
increasingly clear that AI agents will
dominate the landscape of software going
forward. And if you can create
specialized agents on demand that tackle
all of your problems, well then you, my
friend, own the world. And that is why
I'm building Archon. You can think of it
like Bolt, but for agents instead of
front ends and a lot more. So let me
show you a demo of it right now and then
stick around because I'll share my crazy
vision for the project as well. So
Archon can be run in two ways. First, as
a standalone app with a dedicated
interface that I'll show later, but
also, and this is what gets me really
excited, you can use Archon as an engine
to build AI agents within AI IDEs like
I'm showing Windswept right here. You
can do the same with something like
Cursor and Klein as well. And so within
my Windswept, this is using the model
context protocol from Claude, I
literally have Archon as a tool for
Windswept to use. kind of think of it as
a sub-agent. When Windswept realizes it
needs that specialized agent
intelligence, it'll invoke Archon to
generate the code and then that code
will be returned to Windswept and then
implement it straight away in my
development environment. It is super
neat. And so going over to this
interface that I'll cover more later for
Archon, I have this service up and
running for Archon, which is the core of
my MCP server. And then I even have an
MCP tab here that shows you for each of
these coding assistants the exact
configuration to put in for MCP and how
to do all that So I make it super easy
to get up and running with Windswept,
Cursor, and Klein for Archon. All right,
so now let's give Archon a spin in
Windswept. I'm just going to create a
very basic agent right now. In more
dedicated videos later on, I'll build
out more complex use cases and it just
will make more sense as I build out
Archon. So right here, simple AI agent
that uses the Brave API to search the
web. And we can see right away that
Windswept is getting into using the
Archon tools and now it is actually
invoking our agent with this tool call
right here. And we'll see in a little
bit that we can watch the logs in the
Archon UI as well when it's making the
request to our MCP server. And the thing
that I want to really emphasize here is
that you can use a generalist AI coder
like Windswept. Like I can go and
reference the Pydantic AI documentation
or the LangGraph documentation like this
to have Windswept build these agents
with the same frameworks that Archon
uses. But because these AI IDEs are so
generalist, it never works as well as I
want it to. And that's why we need
something specialized like Archon that
knows how to work with these frameworks
through instructions that we give it,
through better rag retrieval from the
documentation. So many opportunities
that we have to implement these
specializations. And so right here, we
got the result back from Archon. It told
Windswept the files to create. And so it
now it's going ahead and creating these
all in my development environment
following the exact structure that I
tell Archon to produce. So we have this
agent right here that is producing
literally perfect Pydantic AI code. I'm
just kind of glossing over this right
here, but this looks perfect. And then
it generates an .env.example file. So it
thinks about things like our environment
variables and the requirements that we
have as well. And even generates a
readme that helps us get started with
this agent, which is just absolutely
beautiful. And we can even go back here
and ask it to iterate on the agent. And
then Archon will be invoked again to
update the code for the agent. And all
the updates that it gives back to
Windswept, Windswept or your AI IDE will
edit the necessary files so you don't
have to rewrite anything from scratch.
And this entire time within the UI for
Archon, we can see the logs. Like these
are the logs from when we used Archon
just now and then any future iterations
will show up here in real time as well.
So it's easy to track everything
happening in the MCP server as well.
It's just such a good combination to use
Archon along with an AI IDE because we
don't want to build another VS Code
fork. We want to focus on creating
Archon as as the specialized engine to
right now work with Pydantic AI and
LangGraph, but also I want to implement
in the future basically every framework
that we have like CrewAI, LlamaIndex,
and AutoGen, all of these so that Archon
can be this AI agent generator. And so
super cool stuff. It does take a couple
of extra credits cuz you have to use the
LLM calls in both Archon and your AI
IDE. But if this can stop a lot of
hallucinations and make it actually
generate agents faster, in the end that
is going to save you a lot of credits.
And that's the most important thing is
we want to be developing agents
correctly and we want to do it quickly.
And so right now, I'll show you how to
get up and running with Archon and then
also I want to show the crazy ideas that
I have to take Archon from its infancy
where it is now into something that
truly is an absolute monster to generate
AI agents on demand. Not only creating
the code here, but also iterating
autonomously and running these agents
itself. That is going to be the dream.
So here is the GitHub repository for
Archon, which I'll have a link to in the
description of this video. And I have
covered already on my channel how I
built Archon from scratch. So I'll link
to that video right here. But
essentially, Archon uses a combination
of my two favorite frameworks, Pydantic
AI and LangGraph, for this agentic
workflow that can intelligently build
agents much better than general AI
coding assistants. And I'm building
Archon in iterations for two reasons.
First, I'm building in public. I want
you to be able to contribute and follow
along as I'm building out Archon. And
then also, I'm building in iterations
because I'm using this as a teaching
tool to show you how to build more
complex agents with Pydantic AI and
LangGraph. And so when I have to explain
something more complex like this, I want
to break it down into simple steps. And
so the iterations of Archon are those
simple steps. So starting with a simple
agent, then implementing LangGraph for a
more powerful agentic flow for agent
creation, and then I added in MCP
support in version 3. And then the most
recent version is where I added in that
huge Streamlit interface for you to
manage everything for Archon. And the
reason that I'm focusing on Pydantic AI
and LangGraph specifically is because a
lot of the other frameworks out there
like LangChain, for example, they are
what's called an abstraction distraction
in my mind. They try to implement so
much for you that you lose a lot of that
customizability and control that you
want when you're building your AI
agents. But I don't feel like I lose
that with Pydantic AI and LangGraph. I
do want to integrate other frameworks at
some point though, more on that later,
but that's why I'm focusing on these
frameworks. And so yeah, there's just so
much that you can read here as far as
the vision and future iterations of
Archon. I'll get into that more in a
little bit. But as far as actually
getting up and running with Archon, I've
made it as easy as I possibly could. So
if you scroll down a little bit in the
readme, you'll see the first option to
install with Docker.
stinking easy. You can install with just
Python if you want as well, just a
couple of more commands. Docker is the
preferred way, but either way, you'll
have that Streamlit interface up and
running that will walk you through
setting up everything for Archon like
the environment variables, your agent
service for MCP, your documentation for
rag, and it'll help you knock them out
one by one super quickly. So it is very
easy to get up and running. And I might
do a dedicated video later on where I
show how to get Archon up and running
from scratch, but I hope that these
instructions make it easy enough to do
it for yourself. And I know that people
have already been doing that. So once
you have Archon up and running with
Docker or just pure Python, the first
tab in the interface is this intro tab
that will get you started with
everything that you need to have Archon
up and running either within the chat
interface that we have right here in the
UI or as an MCP server like I
demonstrated earlier. So it walks you
through setting up your environment
variables, your database, which is using
Superbase, the documentation crawling,
which is just Pydantic AI right now, but
I want to use a lot of other docs later
on, and then setting things up for MCP
as well. And so each of these tabs, I
have poured a lot into making absolutely
perfect. So you can set all of your
environment variables right here in the
UI, for example, so you don't have to do
anything with a .env file. And then this
helps you set up everything for your
database as well, crawling the
documentation, making sure you have
things set up, that you have your table
set up before you crawl the
documentation and create everything for
rag. And then we have the documentation
tab, which I won't show this right now.
It's super cool how you can click this
button and it'll run that crawl for AI
Python script behind the scenes to crawl
the Pydantic AI documentation and then
update you in real time as it's
processing each page of the docs, and
then feature sources coming as well. And
then we have the agent service that I
showed earlier, where you can watch the
logs for your MCP server. And then the
setup instructions for your different AI
IDEs, like Klein, Cursor, and WinSurf,
both with Docker. So, if you set things
up with Docker, there's one way you have
to configure it versus the pure Python
implementation, there's another way. And
these configurations are dynamic to your
operating system and the path that you
have to things like the MCP server
script. And then we have the last
section right here. This is what I want
to spend some time on. I created a
dedicated section of this Archon
interface just to detail all of the
future iterations that I want to
implement, because I don't want to just
explain that briefly in the read me. I
want to put a huge emphasis on the big
plans that I have for Archon. So, I have
this dedicated page outlining everything
in excruciating detail, because I want
to show you the vision that I have and
really hopefully get you behind this as
well. So, the first big thing that I
want to knock out next with Archon going
into version five is a multi-agent
coding workflow. And what I mean by
that, I have this graph here that
outlines this nicely. I want to take the
primary coding agent that I just showed
you in the agentic workflow and split it
up into sub-agents that specialize in
different parts of the code generation.
Like one to create the prompt, another
to define the tools for our agent,
another to create the dependencies for
things like database connections and API
keys, and then one to create the
instance of the agent itself and define
things like the large language model to
use. And I want to do this for two
reasons. The first one is there is a
huge use case with agentic workflows to
have different LLMs tackling different
parts of a problem, kind of like we're
seeing right here, and then come
together to aggregate everything into a
final result for the user. And again,
Archon is partially a teaching tool,
this is a great opportunity for me to
demonstrate this huge use case in
agentic workflows with something
practical. And then the other reason I
want to do this is in general, just
because you can give a lot of
instructions to an LLM, just because the
system prompt and all the tools can fit
in the context window, doesn't mean you
should do it, because LLMs can get
overwhelmed when you give them too much
to do. And so, splitting our coder agent
into different sub-agents means we have
these specialized parts of the workflow
that handle different things. So, we
should get much better results. And I've
implemented these kind of workflows in
other projects. It definitely does
improve the results a lot. So, I'm
looking forward to version five a lot.
And then going into version six, I want
to develop a tool library and example
integrations. So, essentially giving
pre-built tools and example agents to
help Archon create new agents better.
Because with the tool library, if we
have something like this, I mean this is
a very preliminary look at what the
configuration might look like. We have
all these tools that are pre-defined for
something like web search or querying a
database. And so, that way, when Archon
builds the agent, it can use a tool that
looks like this that's already defined
in an agent in a very simple way. So,
then instead of Archon having to build
that tool from scratch, it can pull it
from the library and inject it right
into the code. And so, that way, we
don't have to worry about hallucinating
the creation of tools when that's a tool
that's already been built a thousand
times. We might as well just have that
ready to be pulled in whenever an agent
needs something like a weather tool or
the ability to query a database. And
it's the similar kind of idea with
example agents. So, instead of having to
define the structure from scratch for an
agent, it can look at an example agent,
like the weather agent that we see in
the Pydantic AI documentation. So, using
this as its grounding point, what does a
basic Pydantic AI agent look like? So,
it can use this and then build on top of
it for any more complex use cases that
we'd want to make with Pydantic AI. And
then going into version seven, I want to
include the LangGraph documentation
within Archon's knowledge base, so we
have more than just Pydantic AI. And
this is where we get into Archon being
able to work with more and more
frameworks. So, as a starting point,
adding in LangGraph as well, but then I
want to add in CrewAI and Llama Index.
I'll get into this more in another
version, but this is a kicking it off,
essentially making it so that instead of
it being hardcoded to use Pydantic AI
for everything, we can start to
incorporate other frameworks, allow the
user to choose which framework Archon
will build, and maybe even have it
intelligently determine, based on the
agent that it's building, should it use
just Pydantic AI or should it use
LangGraph and Pydantic AI together? And
then once we have in other frameworks,
maybe it chooses to use one of those
instead, just depending on what we are
building exactly. And so, this is an
example of a LangGraph agent, just
showing more complex agentic workflows
that you can't build with only Pydantic
AI. And so, adding in LangGraph to the
capabilities of Archon is just going to
make it be able to build more and more
complex use cases, which we need for the
agents that we have in the real world
solving these important problems for us.
Then going into version eight, we get
back to improving the agentic flow for
Archon itself with self-feedback loops.
Right now, Archon, when it produces the
agent code, immediately goes to you as
the user to give feedback. But what if
you want it to autonomously iterate on
the agent? Sometimes it knows better
than you what it needs to work on. Or
maybe the hallucinations are kind of
silly and it's easy enough for the LLM
to just correct it itself. We want that
kind of power within Archon. So, that's
what we're doing with version eight. And
then going down into version nine here,
we have self-agent execution. This is
going to be one of the more challenging
parts of Archon, but I cannot wait for
this. Because right now, any AI coding
assistant, the generalists like WinSurf
and Cursor, Archon, if they build the
code for an agent, it doesn't execute it
anyway. There's no way to automatically
hook up a database for RAG or to get
another service installed like CRX and G
for local web search. Like you don't
have that functionality. And so, I want
to build that into Archon. So, once it
creates the code for the agent and maybe
gets the green light from the user that
everything looks good, then it would use
the local AI package. I've covered this
on my channel a lot to spin up an
isolated environment with the database,
like a vector database, a SQL database,
uh web search capabilities. It'll have
that all packaged together ready for the
AI agent to hook into. So, we would
create the agent as a container, bake it
into a Docker Compose stack with all
these other services, so it has this
environment ready to execute right away.
And this gets into so many more
possibilities in the future as well,
being able to automatically test and
execute these agents and really improve
that autonomous iteration. So, it's more
than just the LLM reasoning about the
code that was outputted, but it can
literally test the agent and then see
any errors and work on it that way. So,
I just can't wait for this. And then I
alluded to this a lot already, but for
version 10, I want to implement
multi-framework support. So, Pydantic
AI, LangGraph, LangChain, Agno, CrewAI,
and Llama Index are all the big ones
that I know of. And even though Pydantic
AI and LangGraph are my favorites, I
know that people have different
preferences and there are reasons to use
other ones, maybe if you want something
more simple like CrewAI, for example.
So, I want Archon to support all of
that. And then going into version 11, an
autonomous framework learning process.
So, essentially, whenever Archon creates
a good agent or defines good tools and
it iterates and tests and confirms that,
I want it to add that to its examples
and to the tool library, so that it can
continuously give itself better examples
and tools to have this self-improvement
process. I think that would just be so
cool. Maybe even doing things like
adjusting its own system prompt as well
as it iterates over time and realizes
what makes the agents work the best. So,
very far out there. I mean, these last
few that we have are definitely more
advanced things, but I would love to get
to this point. Also, probably a lot more
versions coming later as well. We're up
to version 13 already, but yeah, there's
so many ways that we could take Archon
much, much further even. And then going
on to version 12, advanced RAG
techniques. Cuz right now, the methods
that I have for exploring the knowledge
base with RAG, they work pretty well,
but I haven't implemented that many
advanced techniques. Things like hybrid
search, reranking, uh query
decomposition, or better chunking
through things like hierarchical
chunking. There's a lot of opportunities
that we have here to make it so that
Archon can understand and use the
documentation for all of our different
frameworks much better. And then the
last version that I have, at least for
now, is the MCP agent marketplace. So,
being able to take these agents that we
built with Archon and publish them to a
marketplace, an MCP marketplace, so that
other people can bring them in as
sub-agents to use within their AI IDEs
or any other MCP clients. So, just like
Archon is a tool, a sub-agent that an
MCP client can use, the agents itself
produces can also be used as sub-agents.
It gets very meta here. Uh again, I
don't want to dive into everything that
would be involved with this, but I think
this would just be so cool. It's just a
way for everything that Archon creates
to be reusable by other people and
shared in something like an MCP agent
marketplace. Then for future
integrations, I don't know exactly which
version these will fit into, but I want
to integrate with these different
services. So, starting with LangSmith
here, this is LangChain's tracing and
monitoring platform. It just gives you a
very good inside scoop with what's
happening with your agentic workflows.
It'll help us better debug Archon and
the agents that Archon creates. So,
definitely want to integrate with
LangSmith at some point. Also could use
something like LangFuse as well. So,
there's a couple different options here,
but since we're working with LangGraph
as one of the core components to Archon,
I think LangSmith certainly makes sense.
And then also an MCP marketplace. And
this is different than version 13. So,
this is for publishing Archon agents to
MCP marketplaces, but I'm talking about
actually having Archon in MCP
marketplaces, so that people can use it
as an MCP server directly through there.
So, they can run everything without
having to go through my GitHub repo and
get everything set up themselves. I
think this would be super cool.
And then also other frameworks besides
Pydantic AI. Obviously, this is covered
in version 10. So, this one I know where
it'd slot in. A couple of these others
I'm not sure exactly which version I'd
add them in, but this one is very
clear-cut here.
And then also other vector databases
besides Superbase. A lot of really
popular options that I have listed out
here. I think it'd be good because
people appreciate different vector
databases for different things. Like
Quadrant is faster than Superbase, and
you can also self-host it. Pinecone runs
serverless. It's not open source, but
it's very, very fast. So, there's
reasons to use different ones. It'd be
good to integrate that as well. And then
last of all, the local AI package, which
I want to integrate specifically for
version 9 when we have the self-agent
execution. So, I know where this one
slots in as well. But, this will just be
so cool to tie everything with Arkon to
the local AI package that I also have
been pouring my heart and soul into. So,
that is literally everything as far as
future integrations and future
iterations of Arkon. So many exciting
things planned. And yeah, if you're not
pumped about this, I don't know what to
tell you because I myself am just so
stoked for what Arkon is now and what
it's going to turn into as I build it
out and as we build it out together. So,
that is Arkon and the awesome plans that
I have for it in a nutshell. And I
encourage you to be a part of this
journey. Follow along as I build it out.
Contribute if you're interested, and
just try it out and suggest features for
me. And the last thing that I want to
say really quick is that Arkon is the
perfect example of what I try to do on
my channel. I try to build agents that
are complex enough to be powerful,
practical, and not easily replaced, but
also build them in a way where I can
break down these complex topics into
things that are easy to understand for
you, so I can teach you best how to
build AI agents. So, if you appreciated
this content, and you're looking forward
to more things Arkon and AI agents, I
would really appreciate a like and a
subscribe. And with that, I will see you
in the next video.